KRITIK SAH

WEB DEVELOPER



- +91 7021245436
- kritiksahco@gmail.com
- Mumbai / Bangalore, India
- in <u>linkedin.com/in/kritiksah/</u>
- cryptolancer.in Portfolio
- youtube.com/itrebels
- English, Hindi & Marathi
- 📅 g<u>ithub/kritik-sah</u>
- / linktr.ee/kritik

SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- NodeJS/javascript knowledge
- React, Redux, Next. js experience
- Mongodb, postman
- On page SEO
- · Good understanding of web3 tech
- Solidity, Ethers.js, Wagmi, foundry EVM chains.
- Git/Github & version control
- PM Tools (Jira for scrum/agile)
- Good Communication
- HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind css
 , SCSS experience
- CMS like Wordpress.

PROFILE

Greetings! I'm Kritik Sah, a front-end developer with 3+ years experience. My journey includes frontend leadership at a web3 firm, contributions to a marketing agency and online pharmacy e-com projects, and a strong passion for user-centric UI and open-source.

EXPERIENCE

SDE (REACT, NEXTJS, WEB3, REACT NATIVE)

ZOWORLD LIMITED

Nov 2023 - present

 I worked with Zo World, as a frontend dev, Learned basics of react native and built an android tv application, and build there admin, House Keeping dashboards. Learned the best practices and typescript and how to write structured and maintainable code.

FRONTEND DEVELOPER (REACT, NEXTJS, WEB3)

Omega Athena Technology Private Ltd / DAOstruct Mar 2023 - Oct 2023

 I enhanced my React and Next.js skills while spearheading the front-end development for an early-stage startup's MVP, concurrently improving on-page SEO, delving into the Web3 ecosystem, attending relevant events, and honing project management abilities as a founding front-end developer.

SDE I - FRONTEND (REACTJS, REDUX)

Intellihealth Solutions Pvt. Ltd. / Truemeds

Nov 2022 - Mar 2023

 I worked with Truemeds, a digital pharmacy and consultancy startup, on various admin and management portals, enhancing my React.js skills in the process.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (MATHEMATICS)

Mumbai University

2018 - 2021

HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Maharashtra Board

2016 - 2018

AWARDS

- Polygon Road to Web3 Hackathon
 Winner Badge.
- Polygon Road to Web3 Hackathon
 Participant Badge
- Web3 Twitter Buidler moralis

PROJECTS

- Portfolio
- ServicesStrategy.com
- infinitelearning.org.in
- Fitndur
- Cocktail recipe application
- NASA PID Next 13 application
- Bank Dapp with smart contract
- NFT Gating website(Dapp)

LEARNING

- Smart contract development & testing
- Professional video editing
- Videography
- Community building
- How to enjoy my life ;p

JR. FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Tonic WorldWide pvt. Ltd.

Aug 2021 - Oct 2022

In my first IT job as a self-taught developer, I gained confidence
and knowledge, working on numerous web projects, creating over
100+ mailers in six months, improving various skills including
blogging, phpMyAdmin, Photoshop, and cleaning PHP and MySQL
backend code (though I'm still learning in this area), with a primary
focus on frontend technologies like HTML, CSS, Bootstrap,
jQuery, and JavaScript.

CERTIFICATIONS

FREECODECAMP.ORG CERTIFICATIONS:

- <u>Responsive Web Design</u>: All about HTML, CSS, and the foundation of web development.
- <u>JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures</u>: Foundation of javascript with Data structure and Algorithms.
- <u>Front End Development Libraries</u>: In the Front End Development Libraries Certification, I learned how to style our site quickly with Bootstrap & how to create powerful Single Page Applications (SPAs) with React and Redux.
- Data Visualization: Data Visualization with D3.

UDEMY COURSE CERTIFICATIONS:

- The Complete 2023 Web Development Bootcamp Dr. Angela Yu
- Linux for Absolute Beginners!
- Linux BASH Shell Terminal Command Basics
- Python: Master Programming and Development with 15 Projects

ALCHEMY UNIVERSITY CERTIFICATIONS:

• JavaScript Fundamentals

OPEN SOURCE



2023 POAP.GALLERY CONTRIBUTOR

open source contribution in poap.gallery website to fix a bug, that was causing blank page website error (crash)



2023 ETHEREUM.ORG CONTRIBUTOR

open source contribution in ethereum.org AKA Ethereum Foundation website to fix bugs in their documentation and other multiple changes.